<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching | Colin Okasaki</title>
    <link>/tags/teaching/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Teaching</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon.png</url>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/tags/teaching/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The recitation method and the nature of classroom learning</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recitation method, also known as the IRE cycle (initiation-response-evaluation) or the CDR method (conventional-direct-recitation) refers to a particular pattern used commonly by teachers. This pattern has stayed in place despite considerable criticism for hundreds of years. The cycle progresses from a teacher initiating an interaction, inviting a response (e.g. asking a question), and evaluating the response before beginning the cycle anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system has been criticized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions asked are mainly low level, calling only for simplistic answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only one student is active at a time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education is reduced to receiving pre-packaged knowledge and demonstrating its retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom conversation is inherently predictable, task-oriented, but unstimulating. Learning becomes sterile, non-emotional, and rule-bound.
This system is ubiquitous around the world. However, about 75% of classtime in an average classroom is spent on the instruction stage. Less than 1% of time was spent on open questions that might ask for complex responses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recitation method has some advantages associated with overcrowded classrooms and the need to teach a rigid set curriculum. It is appealing to teachers because they remain in control of the interaction at virtual all stages and may speed up or slow down to any pace. However students learn little from just hearing teachers talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the major principles of learning is that the learner needs to be actively responding to get anything out of it. They do not necessarily need to respond overtly, they just need to be actively engaged. This is difficult to maintain for the long periods of time that teachers generally speak for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;redundancy effect&lt;/em&gt; identified by cognitive load researchers states that when teachers talk for long periods of time, students are unable to determine which information is relevant and which is not. Effective teachers will explain material extremely well, but very briefly. Students will not learn simply by listening for longer periods of time. Mental focus drops up after perhaps 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two theories underly this drop in mental focus, or &lt;em&gt;mind wandering&lt;/em&gt;. One theory, known as &lt;em&gt;ego depletion&lt;/em&gt; is that one&amp;rsquo;s ability to focus intensely actually literally runs out through exhaustion, measured by brain glucose. So, your mind wanders in order to build up energy for the next upcoming demand that will be placed upon it. The second theory is known as &lt;em&gt;cascading inattention&lt;/em&gt;. This refers to when the mind is unable to clearly process and organize incoming information and fit it into a simple framework and structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative is formulated as the PDC (progressive-discovery-constructivist) approach although the chapter did not explain what this approach entails. Another alternative is tha Paideia model which states that learning takes place in three parts: didactic instruction, Socratic questioning, and coached product. Each of these hsould take up a third of time. However, Socratic questioning is the key and entails more than just students talking. Questions must promote higher order thinking; student talk is a means not an end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time as a global indicator of classroom learning</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your pedagogical philosophy has no bearing on student outcomes unless you spend time on the issues you claim to emphasize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies used four different measures of time (see VL pg. 37) each a subset of the last&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allocated time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time as programmed proactively, on documents and curriculum plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: interruptions, visitors, announcements, transitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: school mandated policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructional time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;actual time genuinely available for instruction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: poor classroom management, allowing time to be hijacked by low-priority issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: managerial skill and time prioritization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engaged time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time student actually pays attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: students not knowing what to focus on, distractions, boredom, fatigue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: clear instructions and meaningful tasks, encouragement, feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic learning time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time when student is learning and responding successfully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: student may be unsuccessful despite effort, gaps in prior knowledge, tasks too challenging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: individualized guidance, encouragement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amount of time dedicated to a particular task varies wildly between different teachers. However the most critical measure of time is academic learning time. Higher tiers can be used to help maximize academic learning time but this is the level that is most consistently correlated with student success. However, just spending time with a topic does not necessarily imply improvement. Rather deliberate practice with a focus on improvement is necessary, with critical components including guidance, instruction, goal setting, and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is particular important for forming deep understanding and connections between topics. Comparing curriculums streamlined to cover the same material in shorter or longer periods of time, there was no difference in test scores on surface-level multiple choice questions. However, free response questions meant to test deep understanding and connections between topics showed wild variation with much higher scores for the students that took the longer courses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The teacher-student relationship</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;em&gt;empathy gap&lt;/em&gt; occurs when people are relatively unable to put themselves in the place of another person. Deep levels of empathy are difficult if you have never had the same experience as another person, or if you are not currently experiencing anything similar. It is easiest to empathize with people whose experiences you are currently mirroring, harder if you have mirrored them in the past, and hardest if you have never experienced them at all. Children in particular do not develop the ability to deeply understand others&amp;rsquo; viewpoints until late adolescence or early adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inability to empathize with each other results in &lt;em&gt;negative escalations&lt;/em&gt;. When one person wrongs or hurts another, the other person retaliates. The first underestimates the harm they incurred and so views the retaliation as out of proportion, which justifies further retaliation, leading to a &lt;em&gt;snowball effect&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;negative cascade&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand establishing positive relationships cascades and results in lasting benefits. Marked improvements have been observed to occur the year &lt;em&gt;following&lt;/em&gt; relationship-based interventions. Longitudinal studies have found persistent and profound benefits to positive teacher student relationships on a decadal scale. These positive relationships may help because they build trust that allows students to make mistakes and ask for help, and builds the confidence in students to try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing positive relationships can be difficult if the focus is on responding to uncooperative students. Social psychology shows that &lt;em&gt;emotional leakage&lt;/em&gt; is common. Hiding emotions is difficult, and when a teacher has negative emotions towards a student the student may realize this. No major theory of learning recommends punitive action in response to difficult students. For example, high school students tend to attribute disciplinary action to the teacher (&amp;ldquo;teacher hats me&amp;rdquo;) rather than accept personal responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a child has an unsupportive home environment, school can become a major source of social and cultural learning. Positive teacher-student relationships can be very influential in personal development in this stage and can mitigate the risk of negastive outcomes for children. On the other hand, positive at-home relationships can buffer negative relationships at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can these positive relationships be manufactured? A study found that just spending a few minute devoted to non-directive non-coercive friendly and child-centered activities positively influences teacher&amp;rsquo;s views for at-risk students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your personality as a teacher</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly a century of research has shown that there is &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; a &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; personality for a teacher to have. Students value being treated with fairness, dignity, and respect much more than they value a particular personality type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been found that children lose respect for adults who violate basic social rules, exhibit cruelty, or otherwise break social conventions. Studies show that very young children possess a strong sense of what is right and wrong and have a deep sense of fairness. They may not behave in this manner, since social judgment and risk assessment develop much later. Almost universally though, basic misdeeds such as being caught lying incur significant degradation of trust and positive relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies show that students evaluate teachers after exposure for as little as 10 seconds. This is an example of the &lt;em&gt;blink effect&lt;/em&gt;. Moreover, these blink assessments are at least somewhat accurate, being correlated with ratings from actual students (although possible this could be an example of the blink effect itself being cemented in place in those genuine students). Deliberate use of warm and inviting body language, direct eye contact, and friendly intonation increased scores on academic tests for 7-year old students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very difficult to detect when children tell lies. Children develop skillful deceit at a very young age and from that point accuracy for telling lies is about 60% (barely above random chance). Rather, we are very good at detecting emotions, but emotions are poor indicators of deceit since truth-tellers often show signs of anxiety when placed under suspicion. Meanwhile liars may prepare for being grilled. Takeaway: do not expect to be able to tell if a student is lying from social cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking help in the classroom is a good thing, and should not be conflated with dependency (relying on a single source excessively and consistently). Help-seeking is associated with &amp;ldquo;mastery goal orientation&amp;rdquo; where students are motivated by factors involving understanding and acquiring knowledge. This contrasts with &amp;ldquo;ego orientation&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;performance orientation&amp;rdquo; where the goal is to look good or outperform one&amp;rsquo;s immediate peers. Both orientatios coexist, but mastery orientation is associated with higher performance and deeper understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are more likely to seek help if they trust their teacher, and if their teacher encourages help-seeking behavour. As students age they begin to associate question-asking with low ability. However, with supportive teachers, students associate question asking more positively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Knowledge an Obstacle to Teaching?</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts in a subject matter area seem to have worse intuition for teaching that subject matter, compared to novices
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In theory this is because they have learned to think about it in a structured and organized way that is not the most effective way to &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; that material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts consistently underestimated how difficult a task is. Novices, having just learned it, know how difficult it is to learn and teach a more basic level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although students rated novices higher and performed better on a post-teaching assessment, the expert-taught students performed better on transferring their learning to a related task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students appreciate being taught by knowledgeable, motivated, passionate individuals
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will rate their best teachers highly on competency, credibility, and fariness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More closely related to student motivation than actual learning. However children learn less from adults they view as ignorant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge about subject matter may make it harder to teach in a group setting, but on an individual level enables you to provide helpful feedback, and contextualize a student&amp;rsquo;s ideas and progress against your own knowledge base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-07/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-08/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-09/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-10/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-13/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-22/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-23/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-24/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-25/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-28/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-29/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-30/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-31/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broad Strokes of Learning</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/core-takeaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/core-takeaways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nine-basic-principles-&#34;&gt;Nine basic principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanations of human learning in terms of innate talent are consistently undermined by research which states that substantial amounts of time, energy, instruction, and effort are required to develop mastery of any subject area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can naturally learn from any information, but to learn effectively that information has to be organized in a way that matches how our minds are organized. Minds are organized differently for different people, and even change as we age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brain has severe, inherent limitations and deep processing becomes impossible when those limits are reached (cognitive load principle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People learn particularly well from other people, through directed instruction and feedback (social learning theory)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People put in a lot more effort when they are confident that worthwhile goals are achievable in the short term. Activating effort and motivation is difficult but not impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term goals are highly motivating, but when they conflict with valuable long-term goals we must develop and use strategies to control impulses and delay gratificatoin (personal regulation through self-control).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learners are humans, and other parts of them &amp;ndash; self esteem, sociality, etc &amp;ndash; must be maintained and acknowledged during the learning process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans are fundamentally social, down to the neurological level. This sociality can be used as a tool (social brain hypothesis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideas about learning that are contradicted by scientific evidence abound. Many of these ideas can be harmful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1-&#34;&gt;Section 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mind may not be &amp;ldquo;designed for thinking&amp;rdquo; and requires time and effort to think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teachers need to recognize how difficult tasks are for beginners. Focus should be not on material but on the actual process of moving from not knowing to knowing. To do this students need a safe environment to acknowledge they don&#39;t understand. We can only holld so much in our cognitive centers, so it is important to ``overlearn&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; basic concepts until it is ingrained and automatic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1-&#34;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students do not dislike school, but tolerate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brain may not be &amp;ldquo;designed&amp;rdquo; for abstract thinking and as a result school is a taxing process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking requires a large investment of resources for an uncertain outcome (understanding) and risk-averse humans prefer to invest these resources in crossing seemingly achievable &amp;ldquo;knowledge gaps&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;knowledge chasms&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-2-&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts may be &amp;ldquo;worse&amp;rdquo; at teaching than novices. The &amp;ldquo;expert blind spot effect&amp;rdquo; explains this:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experts forget how difficult it was to learn something in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a gap between the advanced level on which experts conceptualize of a topic and the short-term learning needs of students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;however, this abstract thinking may help students transfer their learning to related areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2-&#34;&gt;Section 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major ideas about acquisition, memory retention, mental storage, and overload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning need not be conscious, we can only think about so much at once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to develop a vocabulary for learning, and need multiple strategies for learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges: learning styles (i.e. spatial, verbal, kinaesthetic), Mozart effects, multitasking, digital natives, and whether the Internet is really changing how we think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3-&#34;&gt;Section 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-esteem follows success more often than predicting it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building confidence is still important though: in order to maintain positive views of ourselves we build explanations (I cannot; rather than I did not work hard enough) that help our self esteem but hurt our learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning situations are often distracting and knowing how to pay attention to learning is important, but tiring. It is important to know when to stop thinking to save cognitive resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Students Like School?</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no serious evidence that students, on average, actively &lt;em&gt;dislike&lt;/em&gt; school. Rather they are neutral, or mildly positive towards school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A frequent challenge faced by teachers is the apathy of students on an individual level, after working so hard to provide an engaging learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VL puts forward the following hypothesis, following researcher Daniel Willingham:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The human brain is not primarily designed for &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo;: it is designed for sociality, for language learning, for spatial reasoning, etc. Higher level reasoning is not the primary purpose and is, on average, very difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This means that thinking uses up limited resources very quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking someone to invest this level of effort/resources is a hard task. The outcome of a &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo; task could be positive (better understanding) or negative (no progress). Humans are risk-averse and are unlikely to invest effort if they cannot see a likely short-term pay-off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This means the best way to get effort out of students is to show them short-term goals that seem achievable: &amp;ldquo;we are motivated by knowledge gaps, but put off by knowledge chasms.&amp;rdquo; We cannot be curious about everything, and are instead curious about the things we feel we can understand with little additional effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ease with which people can access information has a large effect on how they use that information, and how they feel about that information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rely much more heavily on memory than thinking: it is generally easier to remember a previous result than to derive it from scratch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Teaching</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/remote-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/remote-teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Online Office Hours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom Pro + Canvas Discussions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAing</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/taing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/taing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;expectations-&#34;&gt;Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand early on what the professors expectations are, in detail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I expected to attend class?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we hold regular TA meetings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I grading, writing answer keys, giving guest lectures, holding office hours, holding review sessions, leading discussion sections, responding to online questions, communicating from the instructor to the class, etc?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know what the instructor is emphasizing in class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demeanor-&#34;&gt;Demeanor&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessments</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/assessment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from UWs TA 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/assessing-and-improving-teaching/assessing-student-lerning-grading&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four recommendations from UW:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create clear grading criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate these criteria to students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give constructive feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employ time management strategies when grading large amounts of work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus their time and effort on the things with the highest grading weights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be sensitive about their grades, and ask about grading-related topics frequently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concrete Actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create, communicate, and remind students about clear grading criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create clear expectations about edge cases like late papers, exam timing, grade changes, and typos on assignments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep thorough records of evaluations, and keep for a while after the quarter is over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;promptly document interactions with unhappy students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See further resources on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/teaching/writing-tests&#34;&gt;writing tests&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cft.vanderbilt.edu/guides-sub-pages/grading-student-work&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;assigning grades&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://teachingcommons.stanford.edu/resources/teaching/evaluating-students&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;evaluating students&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/grading-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/a&gt;
 is really hard. First thing to make clear is that I am using mastery-based (i.e. individual skills) rather than norm-referenced (i.e. relative to each other) grading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be consistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure students know what to expect
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is being measured, how is it being measured, what does this have to do with the course at large?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do students need to recall information, recognize patterns, draw inferences, make connections, construct an argument, or what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastery-based grading requires very clear measurable goals and objectives
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Likely want to make some re-adjustment of pre-set expectations based on actual performance. Perhaps the test really was too hard?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cheating-&#34;&gt;Cheating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to stop it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain clearly what is and is not allowed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage students to seek help:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often students cheat because they are doing poorly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage them to schedule a meeting and/or come to office hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give alternating versions of exams (different orders if not different questions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regularly walk around the room and observe students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the exam mark answer sheets in such a way that alterations cannot be made (possibly scan a copy of each exam if possible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give an alternate exam version for make-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homework assignments are difficult to monitor
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UW recommends lowering the amount of the grade HW is worth&amp;hellip;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace homework with in-class quizzes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final projects
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about whether students may have done similar projects in other classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to do when it happens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a specific 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/cssc/facultystaff/report-academic-misconduct&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reporting tool&lt;/a&gt;
 but for TAs it probably goes through the instructor first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classroom Practices</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/classroom-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/classroom-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn everyone&amp;rsquo;s name by week 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce myself:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name/pronouns, background, formality, how/when to reach me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notecards:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preferred name/pronunciation/pronouns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accommodation requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expectations:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grading/deadline criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;classroom policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my commitments as a teacher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how I intend to teach/assess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add codes/course conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;course schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick (ungraded) quiz to gauge background? Self-reported pre-assessment of background knowledge? Resources for filling in gaps? ``Common Sense Inventory:&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; determine whether 15 statements related to course content are true or false?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homework 0: voluntary/mandatory office hour?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is time left to teach, model what the rest of the course will be like. Think about whether registration has stabilized and whether to teach foundational material, or just interesting stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Practices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tie things into what I&amp;rsquo;m excited about. Students can tell if you&amp;rsquo;re into it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give real world examples/applications, particularly in my own work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep up a high degree of connectivity, explain how things relate to other things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/engaging-students-in-learning/promoting-student-engagement-through-active-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Active learning&lt;/a&gt;
 is good. Give students a chance to practice that thing they just learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;office-hours-&#34;&gt;Office Hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most important thing is getting people to come in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give feedback on what&amp;rsquo;s been done so far and offer direction and general guidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them to explain their work and thought process so far
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If that leaves a blank, ask them to solve an easier problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to get them to ask specific questions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is X true?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this specific logic follow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask leading questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to understand what their thought process is, they are likely coming from a different background than me and will think about things in a different way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work through the homework and exams ahead of time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to anticipate sticking points and wrong turns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know and communicate the instructors expectations and emphasize this material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Design</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/course-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/course-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from UWs TA 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/designing-your-course-and-syllabus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cft.vanderbilt.edu/guides-sub-pages/understanding-by-design/#resources&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Backward Design&lt;/a&gt;
:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design a course in reverse by considering
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your learning goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will you assess those goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will you achieve those goals through teaching?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this way everything done in the course is intentional and working towards an established goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-are-my-students-&#34;&gt;Who Are My Students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I even get to learning goals, also consider: who are my students? Why are they taking my course? What can I expect that they already know? What range of backgrounds might the have? What do I expect them to struggle with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-my-learning-goals-&#34;&gt;What Are My Learning Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://teaching.uncc.edu/sites/teaching.uncc.edu/files/media/files/file/GoalsAndObjectives/Bloom.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blooms Taxonomy&lt;/a&gt;
:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A way of classifying increasingly ambitious learning objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three taxonomies for:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge-based goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills-based foals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affective goals (related to values, attitudes, interests)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-will-i-assess-those-goals&#34;&gt;How Will I Assess Those Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both during the course and at the end of the course. Designing 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/teaching/assessment&#34;&gt;assessments&lt;/a&gt;
 is a whole separate can of worms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-will-i-achieve-those-goals-&#34;&gt;How Will I Achieve Those Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get into the nitty-gritty of lesson planning, etc, now is also a good time to write a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/designing-your-course-and-syllabus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt;
. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve done that I think I personally will benefit from calendaring. This will help me remember little things like: two weeks from today is the exam, I need to write it so I can tell students about format, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tests</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/writing-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/writing-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from UWs TA 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/constructing-tests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why am I testing:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to monitor progress and adjust the pace of the course?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to motivate students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to provide data for a grade?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to challenge students to apply concepts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use this information to design the exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is my test consistent with my teaching:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;post/teaching/course-design&#34;&gt;Backwards design&lt;/a&gt;
 will help with this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the test emphasizes analysis and synthesis, make sure class time does as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the students know what to expect?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the test match my stated course goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have I reviewed the material on the test/explained what will be tested?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does my exam test a range of learning?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do students who have not mastered everything have room to demonstrate growth?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple choice exams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to grade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good for testing recall and facts, difficult to test analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure question is clear without reading the answers
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can a prepared student or colleague answer the question as a free response?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid making the right answer stand out for the wrong reasons (i.e. grammer, length)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess the exam questions afterwards:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which questions were most difficult?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were there questions which most students with high-grades missed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of exam format, assessing it after the fact is important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I thought I was testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I tught?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I emphasized?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I really wanted the students to learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If answers to these questions come back no, possibly go back to the Backwards Design and rethink course/assessment structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
