<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notebook | Colin Okasaki</title>
    <link>/categories/notebook/</link>
      <atom:link href="/categories/notebook/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Notebook</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Notebook</title>
      <link>/categories/notebook/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/27</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/fri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/fri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might be surprise-TAing next quarter, so I&amp;rsquo;m focusing all my energy on TA prep today. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to get through the whole UW TA resources page and will be adding notes in 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/teaching&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/25</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/wedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/wedn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make schedule for reading about teaching, and begin browsing UW resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make edits from yesterdays read-through of bypass proposal and look for last couple references&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refamiliarize myself with animal movement case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule:
The UW resource page has 20 sections. The CMU page has 16 sections, and the Visual Learning book has 31 chapters. I plan on reading roughly 1 section, 1 section, and 2 chapters each week, starting next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposal:
Completed and sent to Andrew for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animal Movement:
Looked over the code, tried to re-run it. Got an Anaconda version conflict that I don&amp;rsquo;t remember. Will plan on dealing with that tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook Structure</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/outline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I will outline the structure of my virtual lab notebook, for use during this time of woe. This is necessitated by the current COVID-19 work-from-home crisis, but will be helpful in general as a tool for accountability and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-frequency-&#34;&gt;Post Frequency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will post to the lab notebook at the beginning and end of each year, quarter, and week. I will also post to the lab notebook once per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-content-&#34;&gt;Post Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each multi-day post I will outline my goals for the current time period, along with a self-imposed due date, and (particularly for yearly and quarterly posts) a rough outline of intermediate steps. Then at the end of the period I will summarize my progress toward those goals as well as any major progress in addition to those goals that I undertook in that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each daily post I will outline what my goals were for the day, along with what I actually spent my time on. I will post mathematical and scientific outputs such as documents and plots that I produced that day, and reflect on my productivity and time management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 2020</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/annualpost-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/annualpost-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am just starting this lab notebook now in March 2020, so almost a third of the year is behind me already. That said, one of my big goals for the year, submitting my 
&lt;a href=&#34;content/project/dam-passage-time&#34;&gt;dam passage&lt;/a&gt;
 paper to Proc B, I have already accomplished! Hooray! Hopefully I can continue the momentum now that COVID-19 has well and truly set in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a tendency to be overly ambitious with my goal timelines. I think I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that for now, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to temper my expectations a little bit. I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that with my dam passage project behind me I can focus my time and make more steady progress on my other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete my bypass to the PhD track by April 1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a pretty near-term goal but has been a long time coming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point most of what I need is just to do a bunch of lit reviewing and write up a beefier dissertation proposal than I had the first time round&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit my source inference paper by August 1 2020
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully the timeline on this is not too ambitious. I have a lot of the theory and code done already, but case studies, editting, and background reading take forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up animal movement case study by April 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Set up model and begin data analysis for pollen case study by April 17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up pollen case study by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete third case study by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete all background reading by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete final editing by July 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This leaves one month of wiggle room for things to take longer than I hope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare to TA by September 15
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This fall will be my first time TAing in any capacity since I was an undergrad. I will have more responsibility now than I did then and I want to make sure I am prepared. To do this I plan on doing background reading on teaching and TAing ahead of time. I know the best experience comes from doing but this is all I can do for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse UW TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/just-for-tas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse CMU CollectedWisdom TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmu.edu/teaching/resources/PublicationsArchives/CollectedWisdom/collectwisdom-teachingstrategies.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Read some of the evidence-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://visible-learning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Visible Learning&lt;/a&gt;
 resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t assigned sub-goal deadlines because these are resources I intend to digest slowly over the period. Instead my goal is to do a little of this every week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit my spatial survey design paper by Jan 1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel pretty good about getting the other goals done, if not on time, at least this year. This one is the stretch-iest of all of them. But I certainly won&amp;rsquo;t do it if I give up on it now!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Find good spatial dataset by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete background reading by July 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete simulated case study by September 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete final edits by December 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/24</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/tues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/tues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up virtual lab notebook and COVID-19 accountability structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add references for optimal design chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refamiliarize myself with animal movement case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up virtual lab notebook and COVID-19 accountability structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add references for optimal design chapter
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;including major reference to Lee 1998, which actually does do logistically constrained optimal design but with a different objective function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;propose to compare performance of my method with his, as well as to speed up his method with sparse matrices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 4-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on new idea for logistically-constrained design
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logistically-constrained random sampling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a number of possibilities for how to achieve it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all rely upon being able to calculate or estimate $\pi_i$ and $\pi_{ij}$ the first- and second-order inclusion probabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if we want to estimate them, can we define a Gaussian-like spatial process over second-order inclusion probabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we do that? what is the domain of valid second-order inclusion probability matrices?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Sp20 Week 1</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the week has already gone by, but I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and fill in some meta goals anyway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up virtual lab notebook and COVID-19 accountability structure by Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make schedule for reading about teaching and browse UW 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/just-for-tas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;
 by Wednesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refamiliarize myself with animal movement case study By Thursday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete all references for optimal design chapter in bypass proposal by Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Spring 2020</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/spring-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/spring-post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of this is copied and pasted from my goals for the year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete my bypass to the PhD track by April 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make progress on source inference
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up animal movement case study by April 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Set up model and begin data analysis for pollen case study by April 17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up pollen case study by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete third case study by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete all background reading by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare to TA
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My real goal here is to do just a little bit of reading, every single week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse UW TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/just-for-tas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse CMU CollectedWisdom TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmu.edu/teaching/resources/PublicationsArchives/CollectedWisdom/collectwisdom-teachingstrategies.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Read some of the evidence-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://visible-learning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Visible Learning&lt;/a&gt;
 resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make progress on optimal survey design
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Find good spatial dataset by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete half of background reading by June 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
