<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Colin Okasaki</title>
    <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Colin Okasaki</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language>
    <image>
      <url>/img/icon.png</url>
      <title>Colin Okasaki</title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/27</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week6/mon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week6/mon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-9:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9:30-10:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond to emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning 10:30-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrate pilot study and optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on TAing notes when possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find Neotoma dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Sp20 Week 6</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week6/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week6/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select a pollen dataset to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find a trade winds dataset to use&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run the end-to-end pilot study/optimization procedure (and compare to spatially balanced)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete VL Ch 7-10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look ahead to QSCI HW 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write up the SSN scratch paper before I forget it all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/24</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/fri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/fri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug sampling design code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 10-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look into paleopollen and email Mevin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 11-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write on SSN paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read and take notes on VL Ch 7/8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 2-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write on Mevin paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug sampling design code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 4-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read fun papers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lots of scattered goals today so not all of them actually happened. I did look into the paleopollen stuff but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot there so still need to sift through what may be most applicable. I took some notes on Ch 7 but not Ch 8, and I did read some fun papers. Spent much more than 1 hour debugging the sampling design code but I did finally get it working!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/23</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/thurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/thurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish grading and respond to TAing emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 11-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug covariance parameter estimation for optimal sampling design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-4:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet with Tyler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meetings and lab went well! Implemented profile likelihood method for parameter estimation in the sampling design case study but it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be working. Not sure what could be going on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/22</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/wedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/wedn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just grade all day!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did that! I got almost everything finished just one or two more assignments to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/21</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/tues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/tues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9:30-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Vecchia-Laplace paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 11-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Space-time reading group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for applications of Vecchia-Laplace paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend lecture, grading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did these things! I think the Vecchia-Laplace paper could potentially be useful for the SSN stuff if it turns out that calculating the covariance matrix isn&amp;rsquo;t so so hard, or it could at least be useful for the existing SSN framework. Only got a few assignments done.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/20</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/mon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/mon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-9:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lab checkins and set up for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 9:30-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on TAing notes when possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on optimal design synthetic experiment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Sp20 Week 5</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week5/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Mevin about animal movement and pollen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep working on write-up and looking for datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select and simulate a pilot study procedure for optimal sampling design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read and take notes on VL Ch 7 and 8&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grade for QSCI 483&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did email Mevin and got pointed to a really cool paleo dataset to use for that. Selected a cluster sampling pilot study procedure for the optimal sampling design project. Read and took (some) notes for VL Ch 7. Did a lot of gradnig for QSCI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/17</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/fri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/fri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-10&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond to emails&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 10-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lab meeting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 11-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write up animal movement case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read and take notes on VL Ch 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 2-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for wind speed data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on sampling design case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 4-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on SSN modeling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did all these things although I did not finish writing up the animal movement case study &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more background to include. Read and took notes on both VL Ch 5 and 6. Turns out the pollen dataset that I thought was from AAAAI/NAB was actually not. It is more paleoecological than really pollen counts that we&amp;rsquo;re looking for. Only real pollen counts I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to find so far are AAAAI and EAN (Europe) both of which are closely guarded and cannot be made public. I&amp;rsquo;d really like to use a public dataset so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure what to do about this&amp;hellip;however I did find a wind speed dataset that seems to be pretty decent although right now it only seems to be marine measurements so I&amp;rsquo;m trying to see if there&amp;rsquo;s a land-based sister dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The recitation method and the nature of classroom learning</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-06/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recitation method, also known as the IRE cycle (initiation-response-evaluation) or the CDR method (conventional-direct-recitation) refers to a particular pattern used commonly by teachers. This pattern has stayed in place despite considerable criticism for hundreds of years. The cycle progresses from a teacher initiating an interaction, inviting a response (e.g. asking a question), and evaluating the response before beginning the cycle anew.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This system has been criticized as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Questions asked are mainly low level, calling only for simplistic answers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only one student is active at a time&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education is reduced to receiving pre-packaged knowledge and demonstrating its retention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Classroom conversation is inherently predictable, task-oriented, but unstimulating. Learning becomes sterile, non-emotional, and rule-bound.
This system is ubiquitous around the world. However, about 75% of classtime in an average classroom is spent on the instruction stage. Less than 1% of time was spent on open questions that might ask for complex responses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recitation method has some advantages associated with overcrowded classrooms and the need to teach a rigid set curriculum. It is appealing to teachers because they remain in control of the interaction at virtual all stages and may speed up or slow down to any pace. However students learn little from just hearing teachers talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the major principles of learning is that the learner needs to be actively responding to get anything out of it. They do not necessarily need to respond overtly, they just need to be actively engaged. This is difficult to maintain for the long periods of time that teachers generally speak for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;redundancy effect&lt;/em&gt; identified by cognitive load researchers states that when teachers talk for long periods of time, students are unable to determine which information is relevant and which is not. Effective teachers will explain material extremely well, but very briefly. Students will not learn simply by listening for longer periods of time. Mental focus drops up after perhaps 10 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two theories underly this drop in mental focus, or &lt;em&gt;mind wandering&lt;/em&gt;. One theory, known as &lt;em&gt;ego depletion&lt;/em&gt; is that one&amp;rsquo;s ability to focus intensely actually literally runs out through exhaustion, measured by brain glucose. So, your mind wanders in order to build up energy for the next upcoming demand that will be placed upon it. The second theory is known as &lt;em&gt;cascading inattention&lt;/em&gt;. This refers to when the mind is unable to clearly process and organize incoming information and fit it into a simple framework and structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative is formulated as the PDC (progressive-discovery-constructivist) approach although the chapter did not explain what this approach entails. Another alternative is tha Paideia model which states that learning takes place in three parts: didactic instruction, Socratic questioning, and coached product. Each of these hsould take up a third of time. However, Socratic questioning is the key and entails more than just students talking. Questions must promote higher order thinking; student talk is a means not an end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/16</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/thurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/thurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on animal movement and synthetic data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-4:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet with Tyler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found the bug in my animal movement code!!! Finally I can move on to other parts of this case study. Ran MCMC and it is giving me good and reasonable answers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time as a global indicator of classroom learning</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-05/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Your pedagogical philosophy has no bearing on student outcomes unless you spend time on the issues you claim to emphasize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies used four different measures of time (see VL pg. 37) each a subset of the last&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allocated time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time as programmed proactively, on documents and curriculum plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: interruptions, visitors, announcements, transitions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: school mandated policy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructional time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;actual time genuinely available for instruction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: poor classroom management, allowing time to be hijacked by low-priority issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: managerial skill and time prioritization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engaged time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time student actually pays attention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: students not knowing what to focus on, distractions, boredom, fatigue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: clear instructions and meaningful tasks, encouragement, feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic learning time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;time when student is learning and responding successfully&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;problems: student may be unsuccessful despite effort, gaps in prior knowledge, tasks too challenging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;improved by: individualized guidance, encouragement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amount of time dedicated to a particular task varies wildly between different teachers. However the most critical measure of time is academic learning time. Higher tiers can be used to help maximize academic learning time but this is the level that is most consistently correlated with student success. However, just spending time with a topic does not necessarily imply improvement. Rather deliberate practice with a focus on improvement is necessary, with critical components including guidance, instruction, goal setting, and feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time is particular important for forming deep understanding and connections between topics. Comparing curriculums streamlined to cover the same material in shorter or longer periods of time, there was no difference in test scores on surface-level multiple choice questions. However, free response questions meant to test deep understanding and connections between topics showed wild variation with much higher scores for the students that took the longer courses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/15</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/wedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/wedn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond to Sándor and find spatial dataset&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes on VL Ch 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on SNN modeling math&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did most of these things. Started working on the synthetic data case study for the optimization project.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/14</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/tues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/tues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9:30-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continue work on animal movement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NSF Activity Report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished the activity report, held office hours, worked on movement. Still stumped by my movement bugs. I&amp;rsquo;m getting not-PSD errors from a function that should not possibly be able to produce a non-PSD matrix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/13</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/mon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week4/mon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-9:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lab checkins and set up for the week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 9:30-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug animal movement code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While animal movement code is running, work on VL, then SNN math&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on TAing notes when possible&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on NSF progress report&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Worked on animal movement code. It seems as though my bug is the &amp;ldquo;wiggles&amp;rdquo; common to FEM advection-type equations so I am attempting to implement FD. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too hard for this simple example and is slightly better practice anyways. Spent pretty much all day on that however.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/10</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/fri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/fri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on animal movement case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make notes on VL Ch 3 and 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 2-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Mevin and Sándor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on pollen case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mostly worked on the case study. Made some notes on VL Ch 3 but the movement stuff was very buggy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The teacher-student relationship</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-03/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An &lt;em&gt;empathy gap&lt;/em&gt; occurs when people are relatively unable to put themselves in the place of another person. Deep levels of empathy are difficult if you have never had the same experience as another person, or if you are not currently experiencing anything similar. It is easiest to empathize with people whose experiences you are currently mirroring, harder if you have mirrored them in the past, and hardest if you have never experienced them at all. Children in particular do not develop the ability to deeply understand others&amp;rsquo; viewpoints until late adolescence or early adulthood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inability to empathize with each other results in &lt;em&gt;negative escalations&lt;/em&gt;. When one person wrongs or hurts another, the other person retaliates. The first underestimates the harm they incurred and so views the retaliation as out of proportion, which justifies further retaliation, leading to a &lt;em&gt;snowball effect&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;negative cascade&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand establishing positive relationships cascades and results in lasting benefits. Marked improvements have been observed to occur the year &lt;em&gt;following&lt;/em&gt; relationship-based interventions. Longitudinal studies have found persistent and profound benefits to positive teacher student relationships on a decadal scale. These positive relationships may help because they build trust that allows students to make mistakes and ask for help, and builds the confidence in students to try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developing positive relationships can be difficult if the focus is on responding to uncooperative students. Social psychology shows that &lt;em&gt;emotional leakage&lt;/em&gt; is common. Hiding emotions is difficult, and when a teacher has negative emotions towards a student the student may realize this. No major theory of learning recommends punitive action in response to difficult students. For example, high school students tend to attribute disciplinary action to the teacher (&amp;ldquo;teacher hats me&amp;rdquo;) rather than accept personal responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a child has an unsupportive home environment, school can become a major source of social and cultural learning. Positive teacher-student relationships can be very influential in personal development in this stage and can mitigate the risk of negastive outcomes for children. On the other hand, positive at-home relationships can buffer negative relationships at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can these positive relationships be manufactured? A study found that just spending a few minute devoted to non-directive non-coercive friendly and child-centered activities positively influences teacher&amp;rsquo;s views for at-risk students.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your personality as a teacher</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly a century of research has shown that there is &lt;em&gt;NOT&lt;/em&gt; a &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; personality for a teacher to have. Students value being treated with fairness, dignity, and respect much more than they value a particular personality type.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been found that children lose respect for adults who violate basic social rules, exhibit cruelty, or otherwise break social conventions. Studies show that very young children possess a strong sense of what is right and wrong and have a deep sense of fairness. They may not behave in this manner, since social judgment and risk assessment develop much later. Almost universally though, basic misdeeds such as being caught lying incur significant degradation of trust and positive relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Studies show that students evaluate teachers after exposure for as little as 10 seconds. This is an example of the &lt;em&gt;blink effect&lt;/em&gt;. Moreover, these blink assessments are at least somewhat accurate, being correlated with ratings from actual students (although possible this could be an example of the blink effect itself being cemented in place in those genuine students). Deliberate use of warm and inviting body language, direct eye contact, and friendly intonation increased scores on academic tests for 7-year old students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very difficult to detect when children tell lies. Children develop skillful deceit at a very young age and from that point accuracy for telling lies is about 60% (barely above random chance). Rather, we are very good at detecting emotions, but emotions are poor indicators of deceit since truth-tellers often show signs of anxiety when placed under suspicion. Meanwhile liars may prepare for being grilled. Takeaway: do not expect to be able to tell if a student is lying from social cues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seeking help in the classroom is a good thing, and should not be conflated with dependency (relying on a single source excessively and consistently). Help-seeking is associated with &amp;ldquo;mastery goal orientation&amp;rdquo; where students are motivated by factors involving understanding and acquiring knowledge. This contrasts with &amp;ldquo;ego orientation&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;performance orientation&amp;rdquo; where the goal is to look good or outperform one&amp;rsquo;s immediate peers. Both orientatios coexist, but mastery orientation is associated with higher performance and deeper understanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students are more likely to seek help if they trust their teacher, and if their teacher encourages help-seeking behavour. As students age they begin to associate question-asking with low ability. However, with supportive teachers, students associate question asking more positively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/9</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/thurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/thurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make edits to animal movement modeling section&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-4:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet with Tyler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did these things! Was hoping to finish the animal movement section but it didn&amp;rsquo;t quite happen. Gotta make some decisions about presenting IOU vs OUF results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/8</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/wedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/wedn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write personal statement and finish all my portion of the concurrent MS application&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend class and read VL Ch 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Mevin&amp;rsquo;s sources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finished application by 11:30. Got Dirichlet BC code up and running and am not seeing any obvious bugs right away. Looking good! Skimmed VL Ch 3 and Ch 4, will take notes tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/7</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/tues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/tues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Visible Learning Chapter 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold office hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes on VL Ch 3 and read VL Ch 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Sándor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Got side tracked with adminstrative stuff again. Evidently I have to formally apply to the concurrent MS program in the stats department so that will take up much of my week. I did get the Dirichlet code up and running although there are probably a few lingering bugs. MCMC run is going now. Did not get to VL or emailing Sándor, although I actually looked at his email and there is not too much to respond to directly. I do owe him an update soon though.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/6</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/mon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/mon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prep for the week and finish up my preliminary analysis for the spatial stream network model&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 11-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to run it at least once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TAing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at bypass responses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning stuff went well but I fell into administrative tasks and did not get the code done. I did email my committee, email with Erica about my TAing position, and email with the stats department about the concurrent master&amp;rsquo;s program. I took a brief look at Mevin&amp;rsquo;s response in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Sp20 Week 3</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week3/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still need to finish up my Dirichlet BC code from last week but I got a lot off my plate! I am done with the bypass and the dam passage paper and can get back to research more-or-less full time (less my new TAing position). My next few goals for spring quarter are all focused on my source project, but I would like to make some more progress on the optimal design front to keep some forward momentum on that front.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to spend this week doing a mix of: finishing up the Dirichlet code and hopefully the animal movement case study, TAing, and responding to feedback from my bypass proposal. So my goals are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish up Dirichlet BC code by Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Visible Learning Chapters 3 and 4 by Wednesday/Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Debug animal movement code and get it run at least once by Thursday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Respond to Sándor&amp;rsquo;s email by Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read two of Mevin&amp;rsquo;s suggested papers by Wednesday, the rest by Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finished up the Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read but have not yet taken notes on VL Chs 3 and 4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ran the animal movement code many times, but still debugging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still need to get back to Mevin and Sándor with updates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/3</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/fri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/fri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on QSCI483 stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made some really good progress on Dirichlet BC stuff, but did not manage to get the code to a working point. I feel like I have a good handle on QSCI for this week, and I made some good progress on stream network analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/2</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/thurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/thurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look at QSCI stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Made some good progress on remembering how all the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/courses/qsci-483/linear-algebra/math-diagnostics&#34;&gt;model diagnostics&lt;/a&gt;
 work. Taking this as an opportunity to go beyond what the course really calls for and cement my understanding of these things because they&amp;rsquo;re important to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lab went well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dirichlet BC stuff is chugging along. I definitely did something wrong last time, I think, because I&amp;rsquo;m running into new challenges. Good that I&amp;rsquo;m reimplementing it. I think I have figured out how to deal with these challenges (i.e. get sparse posterior $Q_u$ and then sample from $f$ as a degenerate MVN conditional on $u$.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Knowledge an Obstacle to Teaching?</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-02/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts in a subject matter area seem to have worse intuition for teaching that subject matter, compared to novices
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In theory this is because they have learned to think about it in a structured and organized way that is not the most effective way to &lt;em&gt;learn&lt;/em&gt; that material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts consistently underestimated how difficult a task is. Novices, having just learned it, know how difficult it is to learn and teach a more basic level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although students rated novices higher and performed better on a post-teaching assessment, the expert-taught students performed better on transferring their learning to a related task&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students appreciate being taught by knowledgeable, motivated, passionate individuals
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students will rate their best teachers highly on competency, credibility, and fariness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More closely related to student motivation than actual learning. However children learn less from adults they view as ignorant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge about subject matter may make it harder to teach in a group setting, but on an individual level enables you to provide helpful feedback, and contextualize a student&amp;rsquo;s ideas and progress against your own knowledge base.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 4/1</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/wedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/wedn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes from Visible Learning Chapter 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attend class and continue looking at QSCI HW 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrote up some 
&lt;a href=&#34;/courses/gaussian-processes&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;
 so that I can stop rederiving/looking up common GP/MVN properties that I need to use. Also included on there the math for Dirichlet BCs. Now that the derivation is there I can more effectively write the code for the implementation, rather than writing stuff down on paper every time I try to do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forgot to account in my scheduling today for time to edit and submit my dissertation proposal. Did that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrote up notes for VL Ch 2, and continued to expand on my own 
&lt;a href=&#34;/courses/qsci-483&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;
 for QSCI, reminding myself how all the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/courses/qsci-483/linear-regression/diagnostics&#34;&gt;model diagnostics&lt;/a&gt;
 work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/31</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/tues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/tues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look over the rest of QSCI HW 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take notes from Visible Learning Chapter 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1:30-3:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hold office hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When no one shows up finish up looking at QSCI HW 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then read Visible Learning Chapter 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Didn&amp;rsquo;t make it through the whole thing, had to look up some of the model diagnostics Tim is using, but did get through VL Ch 1 and 2. Struggled with website formatting in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-07/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-08/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-09/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-09/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-10/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-11/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-12/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-13/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-14/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-15/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-16/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-17/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-18/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-19/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-20/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-21/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-22/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-23/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-24/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-25/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-26/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-27/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-28/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-29/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-30/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-31/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Broad Strokes of Learning</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/core-takeaways/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/core-takeaways/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;nine-basic-principles-&#34;&gt;Nine basic principles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanations of human learning in terms of innate talent are consistently undermined by research which states that substantial amounts of time, energy, instruction, and effort are required to develop mastery of any subject area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can naturally learn from any information, but to learn effectively that information has to be organized in a way that matches how our minds are organized. Minds are organized differently for different people, and even change as we age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brain has severe, inherent limitations and deep processing becomes impossible when those limits are reached (cognitive load principle)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People learn particularly well from other people, through directed instruction and feedback (social learning theory)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People put in a lot more effort when they are confident that worthwhile goals are achievable in the short term. Activating effort and motivation is difficult but not impossible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term goals are highly motivating, but when they conflict with valuable long-term goals we must develop and use strategies to control impulses and delay gratificatoin (personal regulation through self-control).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learners are humans, and other parts of them &amp;ndash; self esteem, sociality, etc &amp;ndash; must be maintained and acknowledged during the learning process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Humans are fundamentally social, down to the neurological level. This sociality can be used as a tool (social brain hypothesis)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ideas about learning that are contradicted by scientific evidence abound. Many of these ideas can be harmful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-1-&#34;&gt;Section 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mind may not be &amp;ldquo;designed for thinking&amp;rdquo; and requires time and effort to think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teachers need to recognize how difficult tasks are for beginners. Focus should be not on material but on the actual process of moving from not knowing to knowing. To do this students need a safe environment to acknowledge they don&#39;t understand. We can only holld so much in our cognitive centers, so it is important to ``overlearn&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; basic concepts until it is ingrained and automatic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-1-&#34;&gt;Chapter 1&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Students do not dislike school, but tolerate it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The brain may not be &amp;ldquo;designed&amp;rdquo; for abstract thinking and as a result school is a taxing process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thinking requires a large investment of resources for an uncertain outcome (understanding) and risk-averse humans prefer to invest these resources in crossing seemingly achievable &amp;ldquo;knowledge gaps&amp;rdquo; rather than &amp;ldquo;knowledge chasms&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;chapter-2-&#34;&gt;Chapter 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experts may be &amp;ldquo;worse&amp;rdquo; at teaching than novices. The &amp;ldquo;expert blind spot effect&amp;rdquo; explains this:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;experts forget how difficult it was to learn something in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;there is a gap between the advanced level on which experts conceptualize of a topic and the short-term learning needs of students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;however, this abstract thinking may help students transfer their learning to related areas.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-2-&#34;&gt;Section 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major ideas about acquisition, memory retention, mental storage, and overload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning need not be conscious, we can only think about so much at once&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to develop a vocabulary for learning, and need multiple strategies for learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges: learning styles (i.e. spatial, verbal, kinaesthetic), Mozart effects, multitasking, digital natives, and whether the Internet is really changing how we think&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;section-3-&#34;&gt;Section 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-esteem follows success more often than predicting it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building confidence is still important though: in order to maintain positive views of ourselves we build explanations (I cannot; rather than I did not work hard enough) that help our self esteem but hurt our learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning situations are often distracting and knowing how to pay attention to learning is important, but tiring. It is important to know when to stop thinking to save cognitive resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/30</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/mon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/mon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-11:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do QSCI HW and prep for TAing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 12:30-1:30&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read Visible Learning Chapter 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3:30-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on Dirichlet BC code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did the first half of the QSCI HW, read Ch 1, but did not end up having time to work on the BC code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Sp20 Week 2</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week2/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First real week of the quarter and I am surprise TAing! I also found some frustrating uncommitted code from my Colorado trip which I need to reimplement, but rewriting code is often a way to make it better anyways&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make all suggested changes to bypass proposal by Wednesday and send to committee&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read chapters 1 and 2 of Visible Learning by Wednesday/Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the QSCI hw ahead of time to make sure I&amp;rsquo;ve got it down by Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rewrite Dirichlet BC code by Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spent a lot of time on TAing this week, getting back up to speed on the basics of linear regression and model diagnostics. Mostly for myself, I made up a bunch of notes on the 
&lt;a href=&#34;/courses/qsci-483&#34;&gt;math&lt;/a&gt;
 behind these topics, to cement my own understanding, although the students certainly won&amp;rsquo;t need to know much of that. I made it through the first two chapters of Visible Learning, although I still feel like I need to discuss it with someone to really digest it properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t finish off the Dirichlet code but I&amp;rsquo;m close: I got the theory worked out again, and I think I actually had it wrong the first time. I also got my bypass submitted and approved which is awesome and a big relief!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Don&#39;t Students Like School?</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/visible-learning/ch-01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no serious evidence that students, on average, actively &lt;em&gt;dislike&lt;/em&gt; school. Rather they are neutral, or mildly positive towards school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A frequent challenge faced by teachers is the apathy of students on an individual level, after working so hard to provide an engaging learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VL puts forward the following hypothesis, following researcher Daniel Willingham:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The human brain is not primarily designed for &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo;: it is designed for sociality, for language learning, for spatial reasoning, etc. Higher level reasoning is not the primary purpose and is, on average, very difficult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This means that thinking uses up limited resources very quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asking someone to invest this level of effort/resources is a hard task. The outcome of a &amp;ldquo;thinking&amp;rdquo; task could be positive (better understanding) or negative (no progress). Humans are risk-averse and are unlikely to invest effort if they cannot see a likely short-term pay-off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This means the best way to get effort out of students is to show them short-term goals that seem achievable: &amp;ldquo;we are motivated by knowledge gaps, but put off by knowledge chasms.&amp;rdquo; We cannot be curious about everything, and are instead curious about the things we feel we can understand with little additional effort&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ease with which people can access information has a large effect on how they use that information, and how they feel about that information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We rely much more heavily on memory than thinking: it is generally easier to remember a previous result than to derive it from scratch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/27</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/fri/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/fri/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might be surprise-TAing next quarter, so I&amp;rsquo;m focusing all my energy on TA prep today. I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to get through the whole UW TA resources page and will be adding notes in 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/teaching&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did that! I also met with Tim the course instructor to outline my responsibilities as a TA and did some editing on the Dirichlet BC code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Teaching</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/remote-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/remote-teaching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Online Office Hours:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom Pro + Canvas Discussions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TAing</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/taing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/taing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;expectations-&#34;&gt;Expectations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand early on what the professors expectations are, in detail&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I expected to attend class?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Will we hold regular TA meetings?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Am I grading, writing answer keys, giving guest lectures, holding office hours, holding review sessions, leading discussion sections, responding to online questions, communicating from the instructor to the class, etc?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know what the instructor is emphasizing in class&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demeanor-&#34;&gt;Demeanor&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assessments</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/assessment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/assessment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from UWs TA 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/assessing-and-improving-teaching/assessing-student-lerning-grading&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Four recommendations from UW:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create clear grading criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Communicate these criteria to students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give constructive feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Employ time management strategies when grading large amounts of work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect students to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;focus their time and effort on the things with the highest grading weights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be sensitive about their grades, and ask about grading-related topics frequently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concrete Actions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create, communicate, and remind students about clear grading criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create clear expectations about edge cases like late papers, exam timing, grade changes, and typos on assignments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;keep thorough records of evaluations, and keep for a while after the quarter is over&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;promptly document interactions with unhappy students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See further resources on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/teaching/writing-tests&#34;&gt;writing tests&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cft.vanderbilt.edu/guides-sub-pages/grading-student-work&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;assigning grades&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://teachingcommons.stanford.edu/resources/teaching/evaluating-students&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;evaluating students&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;grading-&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/grading-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Grading&lt;/a&gt;
 is really hard. First thing to make clear is that I am using mastery-based (i.e. individual skills) rather than norm-referenced (i.e. relative to each other) grading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be consistent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure students know what to expect
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is being measured, how is it being measured, what does this have to do with the course at large?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do students need to recall information, recognize patterns, draw inferences, make connections, construct an argument, or what?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mastery-based grading requires very clear measurable goals and objectives
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Likely want to make some re-adjustment of pre-set expectations based on actual performance. Perhaps the test really was too hard?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cheating-&#34;&gt;Cheating&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to stop it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain clearly what is and is not allowed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage students to seek help:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often students cheat because they are doing poorly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Encourage them to schedule a meeting and/or come to office hours&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give alternating versions of exams (different orders if not different questions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Regularly walk around the room and observe students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the exam mark answer sheets in such a way that alterations cannot be made (possibly scan a copy of each exam if possible)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give an alternate exam version for make-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homework assignments are difficult to monitor
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UW recommends lowering the amount of the grade HW is worth&amp;hellip;I don&amp;rsquo;t know about that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Replace homework with in-class quizzes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Final projects
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think about whether students may have done similar projects in other classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to do when it happens:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a specific 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/cssc/facultystaff/report-academic-misconduct&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reporting tool&lt;/a&gt;
 but for TAs it probably goes through the instructor first&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classroom Practices</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/classroom-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/classroom-practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn everyone&amp;rsquo;s name by week 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First day:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce myself:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name/pronouns, background, formality, how/when to reach me&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notecards:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preferred name/pronunciation/pronouns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accommodation requests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expectations:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;grading/deadline criteria&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;classroom policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my commitments as a teacher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how I intend to teach/assess&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;add codes/course conflicts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;course schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quick (ungraded) quiz to gauge background? Self-reported pre-assessment of background knowledge? Resources for filling in gaps? ``Common Sense Inventory:&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; determine whether 15 statements related to course content are true or false?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homework 0: voluntary/mandatory office hour?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there is time left to teach, model what the rest of the course will be like. Think about whether registration has stabilized and whether to teach foundational material, or just interesting stuff&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Practices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tie things into what I&amp;rsquo;m excited about. Students can tell if you&amp;rsquo;re into it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give real world examples/applications, particularly in my own work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep up a high degree of connectivity, explain how things relate to other things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/engaging-students-in-learning/promoting-student-engagement-through-active-learning&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Active learning&lt;/a&gt;
 is good. Give students a chance to practice that thing they just learned&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;office-hours-&#34;&gt;Office Hours&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most important thing is getting people to come in the first place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give feedback on what&amp;rsquo;s been done so far and offer direction and general guidance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask them to explain their work and thought process so far
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If that leaves a blank, ask them to solve an easier problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to get them to ask specific questions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is X true?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does this specific logic follow?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask leading questions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to understand what their thought process is, they are likely coming from a different background than me and will think about things in a different way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work through the homework and exams ahead of time
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try to anticipate sticking points and wrong turns&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know and communicate the instructors expectations and emphasize this material&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Design</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/course-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/course-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from UWs TA 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/designing-your-course-and-syllabus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cft.vanderbilt.edu/guides-sub-pages/understanding-by-design/#resources&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Backward Design&lt;/a&gt;
:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design a course in reverse by considering
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are your learning goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will you assess those goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How will you achieve those goals through teaching?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In this way everything done in the course is intentional and working towards an established goal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-are-my-students-&#34;&gt;Who Are My Students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I even get to learning goals, also consider: who are my students? Why are they taking my course? What can I expect that they already know? What range of backgrounds might the have? What do I expect them to struggle with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-my-learning-goals-&#34;&gt;What Are My Learning Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://teaching.uncc.edu/sites/teaching.uncc.edu/files/media/files/file/GoalsAndObjectives/Bloom.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Blooms Taxonomy&lt;/a&gt;
:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A way of classifying increasingly ambitious learning objectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three taxonomies for:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowledge-based goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skills-based foals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Affective goals (related to values, attitudes, interests)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-will-i-assess-those-goals&#34;&gt;How Will I Assess Those Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both during the course and at the end of the course. Designing 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/teaching/assessment&#34;&gt;assessments&lt;/a&gt;
 is a whole separate can of worms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-will-i-achieve-those-goals-&#34;&gt;How Will I Achieve Those Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get into the nitty-gritty of lesson planning, etc, now is also a good time to write a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/designing-your-course-and-syllabus&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;syllabus&lt;/a&gt;
. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve done that I think I personally will benefit from calendaring. This will help me remember little things like: two weeks from today is the exam, I need to write it so I can tell students about format, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/26</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/thurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/thurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fix Anaconda errors and start animal movement MCMC running overnight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start reading UW TA resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think more about second-order inclusion probabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fixed Anaconda error, then discovered issue where some code was not pushed to GitHub. Unable to find the original code (mostly my implementation of Dirichlet BCs), but re-writing it should be a useful (if annyoing) exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Started reading UW resources and made several 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/teaching&#34;&gt;posts&lt;/a&gt;
. Not all of it is relevant just yet, but I&amp;rsquo;d like to get through all of it and start thinking about everything together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Found 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/23357227&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt;
 about random sampling with given second-order inclusion probabilities. It gives results about which inclusion probability matrices (IPMs) are valid (the answer is complicated) and constructed a maximum-entropy distribution for fixed-size sampling with fixed IPM.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts on IPMs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Want to incorporate logistics somehow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we estimate IPMs after filtering for feasible designs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we calculate IPMs after filtering for feasible designs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can we calculate probability of infeasibility for CP(2) designs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do CP(2) designs work in space-time?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s something in here somewhere but it&amp;rsquo;s buried deep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tests</title>
      <link>/post/teaching/writing-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/teaching/writing-tests/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Notes from UWs TA 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/preparing-to-teach/constructing-tests&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why am I testing:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to monitor progress and adjust the pace of the course?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to motivate students&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to provide data for a grade?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to challenge students to apply concepts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use this information to design the exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is my test consistent with my teaching:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;post/teaching/course-design&#34;&gt;Backwards design&lt;/a&gt;
 will help with this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the test emphasizes analysis and synthesis, make sure class time does as well&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do the students know what to expect?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does the test match my stated course goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have I reviewed the material on the test/explained what will be tested?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does my exam test a range of learning?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do students who have not mastered everything have room to demonstrate growth?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiple choice exams:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy to grade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good for testing recall and facts, difficult to test analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make sure question is clear without reading the answers
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can a prepared student or colleague answer the question as a free response?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Avoid making the right answer stand out for the wrong reasons (i.e. grammer, length)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assess the exam questions afterwards:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Which questions were most difficult?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Were there questions which most students with high-grades missed?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of exam format, assessing it after the fact is important:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I thought I was testing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I tught?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I emphasized?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Did I test what I really wanted the students to learn?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If answers to these questions come back no, possibly go back to the Backwards Design and rethink course/assessment structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/25</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/wedn/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/wedn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make schedule for reading about teaching, and begin browsing UW resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make edits from yesterdays read-through of bypass proposal and look for last couple references&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refamiliarize myself with animal movement case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedule:
The UW resource page has 20 sections. The CMU page has 16 sections, and the Visual Learning book has 31 chapters. I plan on reading roughly 1 section, 1 section, and 2 chapters each week, starting next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposal:
Completed and sent to Andrew for feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Animal Movement:
Looked over the code, tried to re-run it. Got an Anaconda version conflict that I don&amp;rsquo;t remember. Will plan on dealing with that tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook Structure</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/outline/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I will outline the structure of my virtual lab notebook, for use during this time of woe. This is necessitated by the current COVID-19 work-from-home crisis, but will be helpful in general as a tool for accountability and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-frequency-&#34;&gt;Post Frequency&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will post to the lab notebook at the beginning and end of each year, quarter, and week. I will also post to the lab notebook once per day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-content-&#34;&gt;Post Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each multi-day post I will outline my goals for the current time period, along with a self-imposed due date, and (particularly for yearly and quarterly posts) a rough outline of intermediate steps. Then at the end of the period I will summarize my progress toward those goals as well as any major progress in addition to those goals that I undertook in that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In each daily post I will outline what my goals were for the day, along with what I actually spent my time on. I will post mathematical and scientific outputs such as documents and plots that I produced that day, and reflect on my productivity and time management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 2020</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/annualpost-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/annualpost-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am just starting this lab notebook now in March 2020, so almost a third of the year is behind me already. That said, one of my big goals for the year, submitting my 
&lt;a href=&#34;content/project/dam-passage-time&#34;&gt;dam passage&lt;/a&gt;
 paper to Proc B, I have already accomplished! Hooray! Hopefully I can continue the momentum now that COVID-19 has well and truly set in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a tendency to be overly ambitious with my goal timelines. I think I&amp;rsquo;m okay with that for now, but I&amp;rsquo;m trying to temper my expectations a little bit. I&amp;rsquo;m hopeful that with my dam passage project behind me I can focus my time and make more steady progress on my other projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete my bypass to the PhD track by April 1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is a pretty near-term goal but has been a long time coming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point most of what I need is just to do a bunch of lit reviewing and write up a beefier dissertation proposal than I had the first time round&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit my source inference paper by August 1 2020
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hopefully the timeline on this is not too ambitious. I have a lot of the theory and code done already, but case studies, editting, and background reading take forever.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up animal movement case study by April 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Set up model and begin data analysis for pollen case study by April 17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up pollen case study by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete third case study by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete all background reading by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete final editing by July 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This leaves one month of wiggle room for things to take longer than I hope&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare to TA by September 15
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This fall will be my first time TAing in any capacity since I was an undergrad. I will have more responsibility now than I did then and I want to make sure I am prepared. To do this I plan on doing background reading on teaching and TAing ahead of time. I know the best experience comes from doing but this is all I can do for now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse UW TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/just-for-tas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse CMU CollectedWisdom TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmu.edu/teaching/resources/PublicationsArchives/CollectedWisdom/collectwisdom-teachingstrategies.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Read some of the evidence-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://visible-learning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Visible Learning&lt;/a&gt;
 resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t assigned sub-goal deadlines because these are resources I intend to digest slowly over the period. Instead my goal is to do a little of this every week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Submit my spatial survey design paper by Jan 1
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel pretty good about getting the other goals done, if not on time, at least this year. This one is the stretch-iest of all of them. But I certainly won&amp;rsquo;t do it if I give up on it now!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Find good spatial dataset by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete background reading by July 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete simulated case study by September 18&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete final edits by December 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: 3/24</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/tues/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/tues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up virtual lab notebook and COVID-19 accountability structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add references for optimal design chapter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 3-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refamiliarize myself with animal movement case study&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morning: 9-12&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up virtual lab notebook and COVID-19 accountability structure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 1-4&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add references for optimal design chapter
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;including major reference to Lee 1998, which actually does do logistically constrained optimal design but with a different objective function&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;propose to compare performance of my method with his, as well as to speed up his method with sparse matrices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afternoon: 4-5&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work on new idea for logistically-constrained design
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;logistically-constrained random sampling?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;a number of possibilities for how to achieve it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;all rely upon being able to calculate or estimate $\pi_i$ and $\pi_{ij}$ the first- and second-order inclusion probabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if we want to estimate them, can we define a Gaussian-like spatial process over second-order inclusion probabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;how can we do that? what is the domain of valid second-order inclusion probability matrices?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Sp20 Week 1</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/week1/post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the week has already gone by, but I&amp;rsquo;ll go ahead and fill in some meta goals anyway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set up virtual lab notebook and COVID-19 accountability structure by Tuesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make schedule for reading about teaching and browse UW 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/just-for-tas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;
 by Wednesday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refamiliarize myself with animal movement case study By Thursday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete all references for optimal design chapter in bypass proposal by Friday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-&#34;&gt;Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did all these things! Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Notebook: Spring 2020</title>
      <link>/post/notebook/2020/spring/spring-post-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/notebook/2020/spring/spring-post-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-&#34;&gt;Goals&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of this is copied and pasted from my goals for the year:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete my bypass to the PhD track by April 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make progress on source inference
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up animal movement case study by April 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Set up model and begin data analysis for pollen case study by April 17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Write up pollen case study by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete third case study by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete all background reading by June 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare to TA
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My real goal here is to do just a little bit of reading, every single week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse UW TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.washington.edu/teaching/topics/just-for-tas&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resources&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Browse CMU CollectedWisdom TAing 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cmu.edu/teaching/resources/PublicationsArchives/CollectedWisdom/collectwisdom-teachingstrategies.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;resource&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Read some of the evidence-based 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://visible-learning.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Visible Learning&lt;/a&gt;
 resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make progress on optimal survey design
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Find good spatial dataset by May 1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sub goal: Complete half of background reading by June 15&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Source Reconstruction for Linear PDEs</title>
      <link>/talk/spacetime-feb-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/talk/spacetime-feb-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
 feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-academic&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;
 | 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;
: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.chat/academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>/slides/spacetime-feb-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/slides/spacetime-feb-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-spde-method-for-source-inference&#34;&gt;The SPDE Method for Source Inference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motivation&#34;&gt;Motivation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollution
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Say, PCBs in the Duwamish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where did it come from?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easy case: point source
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measure all pipe outlets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use regularization method for unknown source&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hard case: non-point source
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;???&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;possible-approaches&#34;&gt;Possible Approaches&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basically this is the advection-diffusion equation
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Possibly with linear decay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing methods
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FFT/Kalman filter (Sigrist et. al 2014)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;complex method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;non-local basis functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;finite-difference/element method (Stroud et. al 2010)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;comparatively simple, very popular&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local basis functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;possibly slower in some contexts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gaussian functional regression (Nguyen and Peraire 2015)
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;also complex, relatively unknown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;basically a fancy &amp;ldquo;kernel trick&amp;rdquo; method&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-math&#34;&gt;The Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our model is $\mathcal{L}u = f$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assume $\mathcal{L}$ is a linear operator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Then we can discretize this as $Lu = f$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We model $f\sim X\beta + Z\gamma + \epsilon$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If everything is normal $[f|d] \sim \mbox{MVN}(\mu_{\rm post},Q_{\rm post}^{-1})$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;proscons&#34;&gt;Pros/Cons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fast, lots of sparse matrices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexible modeling on $f$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requires known physics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requires linear PDE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rigid statistical modeling of everything else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;demo&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stationary distribution of a space-time SPDE process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stochastic perturbation analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More case studies
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animal movement data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Snowpack data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pollen data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling alternative stable state in Caribbean coral reefs</title>
      <link>/publication/coral-reefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/coral-reefs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slowing the Evolution and Outbreak of Antibiotic Resistance</title>
      <link>/publication/antibiotic-resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/antibiotic-resistance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo Academic&amp;rsquo;s Markdown slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Supplementary notes can be added here, including 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;code and math&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
